<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[BETTER ELEPHANT]]></title>
  <link href="http://betterelephant.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://betterelephant.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-06T17:57:06+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://betterelephant.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Better Elephant]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lesser-Spotted Woodpecker spotted on Heygate estate]]></title>
    <link href="http://betterelephant.github.com/blog/2012/06/01/lesser-spotted-woodpecker-spotted-on-heygate-estate/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-01T10:56:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://betterelephant.github.com/blog/2012/06/01/lesser-spotted-woodpecker-spotted-on-heygate-estate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/46360829@N03/7313517234/in/photostream/lightbox/"><img class="left" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8006/7313517234_4e9e191a8b_m.jpg"></a>A <a href="http://www.rspb.org.uk/wildlife/birdguide/name/l/lesserspottedwoodpecker/index.aspx">Lesser-Spotted Woodpecker</a> was seen pecking at one of the plane trees among the <a href="http://elephantandcastleurbanforest.com">Heygate estate&#8217;s urban forest</a> this morning.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/46360829@N03/7313520106/in/photostream/lightbox/"><img class="right" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7075/7313520106_a0e646d99b_m.jpg"></a><a href="http://www.rspb.org.uk/wildlife/birdguide/name/l/lesserspottedwoodpecker/index.aspx">The lesser spotted woodpecker</a> is the smallest and least common of the three woodpeckers that are resident in Britain, and is an extremely rare sight in central London.</p>

<p>The sighting follows on from the recent revelation that bats are roosting in the empty buildings on the estate:</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/BOBKvJKeUoE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p></br></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/46360829@N03/7314530894/in/photostream/lightbox/"><img class="right" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7089/7314530894_1c434d0622_m.jpg"></a>It also follows on from the sighting of a rare &#8216;Natterjack Toad&#8217; in Better Elephant&#8217;s newly installed hydroponic fish pond - an extremely rare sight anywhere in Britain, let alone in central London.</p>

<p></br></br></br></br>
<a href="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7192/6820425154_4f1920f8b3_m.jpg"><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7192/6820425154_4f1920f8b3_m.jpg"></a>
Along with the resident hens and bees, the Better Elephant scheme is seeing the Elephant &amp; Castle&#8217;s biodiversity index raised to unprecedented levels.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/46360829@N03/7314614084/in/photostream/lightbox/"><img class="right" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7096/7314614084_9dd27cca78_m.jpg"></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Better Elephant gardeners praised for their 'blooming beautiful' efforts.]]></title>
    <link href="http://betterelephant.github.com/blog/2012/05/21/better-elephant-gardeners-praised-for-their-blooming-beautiful-efforts/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-21T10:45:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://betterelephant.github.com/blog/2012/05/21/better-elephant-gardeners-praised-for-their-blooming-beautiful-efforts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Better Elephant gardeners have received praise for their &#8216;blooming beautiful&#8217; efforts in a <a href="http://www.veoliaenvironmentalservices.co.uk/Southwark/About-us/News/Press-releases/Grow-your-own-in-the-old-blue-box/">press release</a> by Southwark contractors Veolia today.</p>

<p>The team were mentioned alongside the Pembroke Gardens community gardening project for having made creative use of the council&#8217;s old recycling boxes, which have now been replaced with a new design.</p>

<p><img class="right" src="http://betterelephant.github.com/images/IMG_1966.JPG"> Better Elephant&#8217;s gardeners are leading an initiative to demonstrate the potential for sustainable local food production at the Elephant &amp; Castle. The team include former Heygate residents the Uddin family, who also manage the nearby &#8216;Ivory Arch&#8217; Indian restaurant. The project has involved researchers in urban agriculture from UCL (University College London) and is exploring the potential for <a href="http://www.ruaf.org/sites/default/files/UAM22%20London%2037-38.pdf">local food sourcing to supply local demand</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Better Elephant kicks off growing season with a splash]]></title>
    <link href="http://betterelephant.github.com/blog/2012/03/15/better-elephant-kicks-off-growing-season-with-a-splash/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-15T18:13:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://betterelephant.github.com/blog/2012/03/15/better-elephant-kicks-off-growing-season-with-a-splash</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="left" src="http://betterelephant.github.com/images/fishes.jpg">Better Elephant marked the beginning of the 2012 growing season with a splash this week. The opening of the new fish pond was received with much interest and enthusiasm. Southwark News reported on the event and Southwark council agreed the pond could stay - despite its initial fears over health and safety.</p>

<p>The pond contains a number of fish and will form the base of an aquaponics system, which is part of Better Elephant&#8217;s plan for an edible landscape and <a href="http://www.ruaf.org/sites/default/files/UAM22%20London%2037-38.pdf">sustainable food production at the Elephant &amp; Castle</a>.</p>

<p><img class="right" src="http://t0.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcSFdI-Ok-pHzhQOBgPnKwEQIoKQsz7CedL881d0Qaw4GngZ5zmeJQ"> Aquaponics is a sustainable food production system that combines a traditional aquaculture (raising aquatic animals such as snails, fish, crayfish or prawns in tanks) with hydroponics (cultivating plants in water) in a symbiotic environment. In the aquaculture, effluents accumulate in the water, increasing toxicity for the fish. This water is led to a hydroponic system where the by-products from the aquaculture are filtered out by the plants as vital nutrients, after which the cleansed water is recirculated back to the animals.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sun shines on Better Elephant exhibition]]></title>
    <link href="http://betterelephant.github.com/blog/2012/02/28/sun-shines-on-a-better-elephant/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-28T17:50:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://betterelephant.github.com/blog/2012/02/28/sun-shines-on-a-better-elephant</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="left" src="http://betterelephant.github.com/images/southwarknewsBEarticle.jpg">The sun was shining on our <a href="http://betterelephant.org/images/BetterElephantFlyer.png">Better Elephant exhibition</a> at the Heygate estate on Saturday. Over 100 people turned out in the spring-like sunshine, to view our <a href="http://www.communities.gov.uk/publications/planningandbuilding/introductionneighbourplanning">neighbourhood planning</a> proposal for an alternative regeneration plan at the Elephant &amp; Castle. The exhibition is a response to the current masterplan for the area, which was released to the public last week, and which offers an alternative vision for the Elephant &amp; Castle area.<img class="right" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7183/6934528321_ec11c8611e_m.jpg"></p>

<p><img class="right" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7065/6934528309_8e7a3918b7_m.jpg">
Our exhibition discussed the existing proposals and compared them to the Better Elephant plan, which included the following:</p>

<p></br></p>

<ul>
<li>Ideas for refurbishment of some of the existing homes</li>
<li>Retention of the urban forest of 450 mature trees</li>
<li>Wind turbines located on high-rise blocks</li>
<li>Green roofs and food-growing spaces</li>
<li>Conversion of existing district heating system boiler to biomass</li>
</ul>


<p><img class="left" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7198/6791800232_2f39a4a174_m.jpg">Better Elephant&#8217;s <a href="http://betterelephant.github.com/space">gardeners</a> where also proud to showcase their ideas for community gardening activities. They were out in force preparing for the coming growing season, and inviting other local residents to get involved. The group have begun planting herbs and vegetables in old recycling containers in various location throughout the disused housing estate. Any local residents who are interested in starting their own mobile gardens are <a href="http://betterelephant.org/space">invited to get involved</a>.</p>

<p>After the success of the event, the exhibition&#8217;s display boards will remain in place providing a hub for further information and consultation.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
