<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[BETTER ELEPHANT]]></title>
  <link href="http://betterelephant.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://betterelephant.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-28T18:53:18+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://betterelephant.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Better Elephant]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sun shines on a Better Elephant]]></title>
    <link href="http://betterelephant.github.com/blog/2012/02/28/sun-shines-on-a-better-elephant/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-28T17:50:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://betterelephant.github.com/blog/2012/02/28/sun-shines-on-a-better-elephant</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7183/6934528321_ec11c8611e_m.jpg">The sun was shining on the Better Elephant exhibition at the Heygate estate on Saturday. Over 100 people turned out in the spring-like sunshine, to view the neighbourhood planning group&#8217;s proposals for an alternative regeneration plan. The group is formed of local residents who have become disillusioned with the current masterplan for the area, which was released to the public last week.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7065/6934528309_8e7a3918b7_m.jpg">They are campaigning amongst other things to retain some of the family homes on the Heygate estate, and reinstate some of the original proposals from the 2004 masterplan, i.e. the civic square and the MUSCo (Multi-Utility Services Company).
After the success of the event, the group are planning to leave the exhibition&#8217;s display boards up for a further two weeks.</p>

<br>


<p><img class="right" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7198/6791800232_2f39a4a174_m.jpg">Spring was in the air for the Heygate&#8217;s mobile gardeners too. They were out in force preparing for the coming growing season, and inviting other local residents to get involved. The group have begun planting herbs and vegetables in old recycling containers in various location throughout the disused housing estate. Any local residents interested in starting their own mobile garden are <a href="http://betterelephant.org/space">invited to get involved</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
