<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[BETTER ELEPHANT]]></title>
  <link href="http://betterelephant.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://betterelephant.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-01T09:39:55+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://betterelephant.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Better Elephant]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sun shines on a Better Elephant]]></title>
    <link href="http://betterelephant.github.com/blog/2012/02/28/sun-shines-on-a-better-elephant/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-28T17:50:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://betterelephant.github.com/blog/2012/02/28/sun-shines-on-a-better-elephant</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7183/6934528321_ec11c8611e_m.jpg">The sun was shining on our <a href="http://betterelephant.org/images/BetterElephantFlyer.png">Better Elephant exhibition</a> at the Heygate estate on Saturday. Over 100 people turned out in the spring-like sunshine, to view our <a href="http://www.communities.gov.uk/publications/planningandbuilding/introductionneighbourplanning">neighbourhood planning</a> proposal for an alternative regeneration plan. The exhibition is a response to the current masterplan for the area, which was released to the public last week, and which offers an alternative vision of regeneration at the Elephant &amp; Castle.</p>

<p><img class="left" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7065/6934528309_8e7a3918b7_m.jpg">We are proposing amongst other things to retain some of the family homes on the Heygate estate, and reinstate some of the original proposals from the <a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/82420796/Southwark-Council-2004-Development-Framework">2004 masterplan</a>, i.e. the civic square and the MUSCo (Multi-Utility Services Company).
After the success of the event, we are planning to leave the exhibition&#8217;s display boards up for a further two weeks until 15th March.</p>

<br>


<p><img class="right" src="http://t1.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcTFZZqOTZjKk9JBQ-K-Jj6xrfQcWDZNLn6X26wvKF5nrk-rED67VQ">You can find us between the Cuddington blocks of the maisonettes in the centre of the Heygate estate. These are outlined in red on the adjacent map.</p>

<p><img class="right" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7198/6791800232_2f39a4a174_m.jpg">Spring was in the air for the Heygate&#8217;s mobile gardeners too. They were out in force preparing for the coming growing season, and inviting other local residents to get involved. The group have begun planting herbs and vegetables in old recycling containers in various location throughout the disused housing estate. Any local residents who are interested in starting their own mobile gardens are <a href="http://betterelephant.org/space">invited to get involved</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
